Guide to the John R. Post Collection of Lawrence Clark Powell Material
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3: Miscellaneous
  - The Legacy of a Librarian - Mark Simmons July 2001 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Obituary, Book Talk, New Mexico Book League
  - Librarian/Author Powell dies at 94 2001 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Library Journal editorial, May 15, 2001 news note, April 15, 2001; photcopies
  - Remebering Larry Powell 2001 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Editorial / obituary, John N. Berry III, ed., Library Journal, May 15, 2001
  - Southwest Literature Project: Southwest Books of the year 2001 2001 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Postcard announcement, events to honor the memory of L.C.P., sponsored by Arizona Historical Society, Crowder Hall, University of Arizona, December 13-15, 2001
  - Photograph With Ben Siegel 1981 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Photograph With Ben Siegel
  - Photograph, L.C.P. at lectern March 7, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Photographs n/d
  - L.C.P. with 2 Associates n/d (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Photograph, L.C.P. at desk n/d (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Photograph / Portrait 1954 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Photocopy of L.C.P. "portrait" by Leigh Weiner, featured in Los Angeles magazine, n.d., original photo dated 1954
  - News article photograph Winter 1981 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Buckskin Bulletin, published by Westerners' International, Tucson, AZ
  - Photograph Wih Bea Siegel 1991 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Libraries of the Southwest: Their Growth-Strengths-Needs 1953 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    Papers presented at Conference of Librarians and Writers, Occidental College, April 16, 1955; ed. by L.C.P.
  - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty, no. 6 September 1948 1948 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty no. 1 April 1945 1945 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty no. 2 December 1945 1945 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty no. 3 July 1946 1946 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty no. 4 December 1946 1946 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - The Librarian's Occasional Letter to the Faculty no. 5 September 1947 1947 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Great American Historical Documents: Manuscripts and Books 1949 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    Exhibit booklet, UCLA Library; acknowlegement by L.C.P.
  - Rare Books and Research 1951 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    Exhibit booklet, UCLA Library; introduction by L.C.P.
  - Libraries and Learning...A Rerading List 1956 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    Outline and bibilography for English 195, UCLA Library Occasional Papers no. 5
  - The Last Frontiersman 1957 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    Exhibit booklet, UCLA Library; foreword by L.C.P.
  - Mean What You Say: A Conference on Reporting 1959 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    Proceedings of conference held at UB-Santa Barbara, July 20-23, 1958; UCLA Library Occasional Papers, no. 10, preface by L.C.P.
  - What's Wrong With Librarians? 1957 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    UCLA Library Occasional Paper no. 9
  - Guide to Special Collections 1958 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    UCLA Occasional Paper no. 7; foreword by L.C.P.
  - Libraries and Learning...A Reading List 1958 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    UCLA Occasional Paper no. 5, second revised edition
  - The Southwest of the Bookman Essays from Various Sources 1959 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    UCLA Library Occasional Paper no. 11; edited by L.C.P.
  - UCLA Librarian Clarence Day Award Photo 1960 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    UCLA Librarian vol 13 no 20; photo on p 130, text on p 131
  - Around the World in Sixty Books 1960 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Booklet, compiled by L.C.P., UCLA Library
  - Lawrence Durrell: A Checklist 1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Keepsake, on the occasion of L.C.P.'s Durrell Collection presented to UCLA Library
  - Presentation of Powell Portrait 1962 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    UCLA Librarian, vol 15 no 26, p 181
  - One Hundred Paperbooks for the Library of a Sophisticated Family 1962 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Reprint, UCLA School of Library Science
  - Aldous Huxley 1894-1963 1963 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    UCLA Librarian, vol 17 no 3, p 21
  - Bibiliographical Resources for the Study ofNineteenth Century English Fiction 1964 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    School of Library Service, UCLA; foreword by L.C.P.
  - Lawrence Clark Powell Librarian 1966 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    UCLA Librarian, vol 19 no 6, p 53; lkead article by Hugh G. Dick
  - Kenneth Rexroth -- A Checklist of his Published Writings 1967 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Keepsake, foreword by L.C.P., Friends of the UCLA Library
  - UCLA Graduate School of Library and Information Science: Our Origins and Andy Horn 1984 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    Photocopied ts
  - The UCLA Graduate School of Library and Information Science:Its Origins and Founding 1985 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    25th Anniversary Address, pamphlet, autographed
  - William Andrews Clark Memorial Library -- Report of the First Decade: 1934 -1944 1946 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Introduction by L.C.P., pamphlet
  - William Andrews Clark Memorial Library -- Report of the First Decade: 1934 -1944 1946 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    Hardbound copy of first decade report
  - William Andrews Clark Memorial Library -- Report of the Second Decade: 1945 -1955 1956 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - The Ubiquitous Book in Our Time 1957 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    Booklet, "The Merle Armitage Books in the WIlliam Andrews Clark Library;" title essay by Armitage, foreword by L.C.P.
  - Francis Bacon's Intellectual Milieu 1962 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Booklet, paper delivered by Virgil K. Whitaker, Clark Library, November 18, 1961; foreword by L.C.P.
  - Thomas Willis As a Physician 1964 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    Booklet, paper delivered by Kenneth Dewhurst, introduction by L.C.P.
  - William Andrews Clark Memorial Library -- Report of the Third DevcadeDecade: 1956 -1966 1966 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    Booklet,introduction and essay "Eric Gill" by L.C.P.
  - Neo-Latin Poetry of the 16th and 17th Century 1965 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    Booklet, papers by James E. Phillips and Don Cameron Allen, Clark Library, October 17, 1964; foreword by L.C.P.
  - Homage to Yeats 1865 - 1965 1965 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    Booklet, papers by Walter Starkie and A. Norman Jeffares, Clark Library, October 16, 1965; foreword by L.C.P.
  - Some Aspects of Seventeenth Century English Printing with Special Reference to Joseph Moxon 1965 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    Booklet, paper by Carey S. Bliss, Clark Library, April 24, 1965; foreword by L.C.P.
  - History of Botany 1965 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    Booklet, papers by George H.M.Lawrence, and Kenneth F. Baker, Clark Library, December 7, 1963; foreword by L.C.P.
  - Mercurius Redivivus: Being an Occasional Newsletter from the William Andrews Clark Library; A Facsimile of Three Issues, 1952-53-58 1994 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Keepsake booklet,introduction by L.C.P., 22nd annual reunion of Zamorano and Roxburghe Clubs, October 7-9, 1994
  - Toward A Bibliography of John Steinbeck 1938 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    The Colophon Vol. 111 New Series # 4 Autumn 1938: A Quarterly for Bookmen; includes seperate 1938 bibliography of non-fiction and fiction books by California authors, attributed to Linnie Marsh Wolfe
  - Powell portrait n.d. n.d. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Announcement, unveiling of relief portrait of L.C.P.
  - Some Uncollected Authors -- Lawrence Durrell n.d. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Reprint from The Book Collector; attributeed to Alan G. Thomas and L.C.P., text attributed to A.G.T.
  - Resources Unlimited: Special Collections at UCLA n.d. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Pamphlet
  - D.H. Lawrence and His Critics: A Chronological Excursion in Bio-Bibliography 1940 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    The Colphon New Graphic Series no.4 Vol.1, pg. 63-74
  - The Hand of Zamorano: A Manuscript on California 1829 1956 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    Facsimile reproduction of ms on the Californias ca. 1829, written by Don Agustin Vicente Zamorano; printed for third joint meeting of Zamorano and Roxburghe Clubs; note by L.C.P.
- Series 4: Catalogs
  - Modern Literature 1940's n.d. n.d. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Extensive quotation, introduction to Catalog 20, Ben Abramson's Argus Bookshop, New York, NY
  - Books on the Wing 1951 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Introductory essay in Catalog 31, A catalog of English Books Printed Before 1701, Willian P. Wreden Rare Books, Burlingame, CA
  - Southwestern Book Trails n.d. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Listed in catalog "Books Worth Collecting," Calvin Horn Publisher, Albuquerque, NM, under Books Out-Of-Print
  - A Bookman Looks at Christmas Time 1963 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Introductory essay, Catalog 78, J.E. Reynolds, Bookseller, Van Nuys, CA, Christmas, 1963; 2 copies, 1 autographed
  - The Stagecoach Press n.d. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Introductory essay, Catalog 32, Texas and the West, Price Daniel, Jr., Bookseller, Waco ,TX, 1965
  - POW'S Books 1984 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Catalogue 21, featuring the L.C.P. collections of Anthony Lehman and Jake Zeitlin, Jeff Weber, Rare Books, Glendale CA; 2 copies 1 autographed
  - Ex Libris Lawrence Clark Powell: Selected Volumes ( A -H) from the Library of L.C.P. n.d. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Catalog, foreword, by L.C.P., Books West Southwest, Tucson, AZ; 2 copies, 1 autographed
  - Ex Libris Lawrence Clark Powell: Selected Volumes ( A -L) from the Library of L.C.P. n.d. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Ex Libris Lawrence Clark Powell: Selected Volumes from the Library of L.C.P. 1992 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Catalog 3, foreword, by L.C.P., Books West Southwest, Tucson, AZ; Spring, 1992
  - Ex Libris Lawrence Clark Powell: Selected Volumes from the Library of L.C.P. 1992 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Catalog 4, foreword, by L.C.P., Books West Southwest, Tucson, AZ; Summer, 1992
  - Ex Libris Lawrence Clark Powell: Selected Volumes from the Library of L.C.P. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Catalog 5, foreword, by L.C.P., Books West Southwest, Tucson, AZ; Summer, 1993
  - Ex Libris Lawrence Clark Powell: Selected Volumes from the Library of L.C.P. 1993 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Catalog 6, foreword, by L.C.P., Books West Southwest, Tucson, AZ; Fall, 1993
  - Ex Libris Lawrence Clark Powell: Selected Volumes, part VII from the Library of L.C.P. 1995 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Catalog 7 (8 scratched out on 1 copy), foreword, by L.C.P., Books West Southwest, Tucson, AZ; Summer, 1995; 2 copies
  - Lawrence Clark Powell: The Catalog 1996 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Catalog 9, Books West Southwest, Tucson, AZ; Spring, 1996
  - Final Offering: Lawrence Clark Powell 1997 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    Catalog 10, Books West Southwest, Irvine, CA: Summer, 1997
  - The Library of Irving Whitmore Robbins - Pacific Book Auction 1996 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Auction list, Pacific Book Auction Galleries, San Francisco, CA, March 21, 1996 [L.C.P. not mentioned?]
  - The Library of Dr. Robert K. Larson: Part 1 Pacific Book Auction 1995 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Auction list, Pacific Book Auction Galleries, San Francisco, CA, February 24, 1995; L.C.P. note inside front cover
  - The Library of Dr. Robert K. Larson: Part Two pacific Book Auction 1995 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Auction list, Pacific Book Auction Galleries, San Francisco, CA, September 28, 1995; L.C.P. note inside front cover
  - The Library of Dr. Robert K. Larson: Part Three Pacific Book Auction 1996 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Auction list, Pacific Book Auction Galleries, San Francisco, CA, February 12, 1996; L.C.P. note inside front cover
  - The Library of Dr. Robert K. Larson: Part Four Pacific Book Auction 1997 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Auction list, L.C.P. collection, Pacific Book Auction Galleries, San Francisco, CA, April 25, 1997; L.C.P. note inside front cover
  - The Library of Dr. Robert K. Larson Part Four Pacific Book Auction 1997 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Auction list, Pacific Book Auction Galleries, San Francisco, CA, April 26, 19997; L.C.P. note inside front cover
  - Controversial James: An Essay on the life and work of George Wharton James 1991 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Robert Keith Larson, author, foreword by L.C.P.,The Book Club of California Publication no. 195, San Francisco, CA, 1991
- Series 5: Media
  - Lawrence Clark Powell's Southwest:, Vol. 1: An Essay on th Land 1997, audio cassette (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Audio Book (cassette), written and narrated by L.C.P., Singing Wing Audio, Benson, AZ
  - Lawrence Clark Powell's Southwest:, Vol. 2: Where Water Flows 1997, audio cassette (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Lawrence Clark Powell's Southwest:, Vol. 3: Revista Nueva Mexico 1997, audio cassette (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Lawrence Clark Powell's Southwest:, Vol. 1: An Essay on th Land 1997[?], compact disc (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Audio Book (compact disc), written and narrated by L.C.P., Singing Wing Audio, Benson, AZ
  - Lawrence Clark Powell's Southwest:, Vol. 2: Where Water Flows 1997[?], compact disc (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Lawrence Clark Powell's Southwest:, Vol. 3: Revista Nueva Mexico 1997[?], compact disc (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - The Glowing Heart of the World, Lawrence Clark Powelll's Literary Guidebook to the Southwest,: Arizona and the Deserts 1998, audio cassette (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Glowing Heart of the World, Lawrence Clark Powelll's Literary Guidebook to the Southwest,: Santa Fe and New Mexico 1998, audio cassette (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - The Glowing Heart of the World, Lawrence Clark Powelll's Literary Guidebook to the Southwest,: Indian Country and the Rockies 1998, audio cassette (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Glowing Heart of the World, Lawrence Clark Powelll's Literary Guidebook to the Southwest,: Mythic West 1998, audio cassette (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Henry Miller Odyssey 1995, video cassette, vhs, 00:60:00 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Video cassette, film by Robert Snyder, Mystic Fire Video, Inc., New York, NY; L.C.P. in film[?]
- Series 6: Broadsides
  - A Man Is at His Best: Number One of Southwest Broadsides 1953 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    by Will Levington Comfort, Printed by W.M. Cheney, Los Angeles 1953 6 1/2 x 8 inches Two Colors. 2 copies
  - Two Kinds of People: Number Three of Southwest Broadsides 1953 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    by J. Frank Dobie, Printed by Grant Dahlstrom at the Castle Press, Pasadena 1953. The text is from The Writer and His Region, Southwest Review, Spring 1950 -- 8 1/2x11 inches. Two colors. 2 copies
  - When We Peer into the Colored Canyon: Number Four of Southwest Broadsides 1954 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Haniel Long; Printed by Saul and Lillian Marks, Plantin Press
  - Paso Por Aqui: Number Five of Southwest Broadsides (Box 20, Folder 4)
    By Mary Austin, Printed by Gordon Williams on his Hand-Press in Zelah. Excerpt from Mary Austin's "The Land of Journey's Ending -- 8 1/2x11 inches. Two colors
  - What We Are Here For, by Charles F. Lummis: Number Seven of Southwest Broadsides (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Printed by Lawton Kennedy, San Francisco 1956. Excerpt from the Librarian's Annual Report for 1906. 9x12 1/2 inches. Three colors
  - Bent's Fort, by David Lavender: Number Eight of Southwest Broadsides (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Designed and drawings by Merle Armitage -- Printed by Cole-Holmquist, Los Angeles 1955. 8 1/2 x 11 inches folded. Two colors
  - Trans Pecos, by J. Frank Dobie: Number Nine of Southwest Broadsides (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Printed by Carl hertzog of El Paso with drawings by Joso Cisneros. 1955. From "A Vaquero of the Brush Country" by Dobie. 6 1/2 x 9 inches folded. Two colors
  - Brush Country; J. Frank Dobie: Number 10 of Southwest Broadsides 1956 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    Printed by Grant Dahlstrom
  - The Southwest Broadsides, 1953-1958 1958 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    A descriptive pamphlet entitled "The Southwest Broadsides" was published in 1958 for distribution to Powell's friends. Two copies.
  - The Gospel According to St. Lawrence 1985, 8" x 12" (Box 20, Folder 10)
    Signed by L.C.P. and Mark Sanders; Ward Ritchie, 2 copies
  - Book, Books, Books, by Lawrence Clark Powell 1990 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    6 1/2 x 10;" [embossed, no ink]
  - This is a Fragile Land 1991 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    6 1/2"x 9" Signed by L.C.P.
  - During those Dreamy Hours 1992 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    10 1/2 x 9" Signed by L.C.P.
  - Lawrence Clark Powell 1994 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    9 1/2"x 73/4" Signed L.C.P.
  - The Sensitive Traveler 1994 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    11"x 9" Signed by L.C.P.
  - Theodore M. Lilienthal 1972 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    Note by L.C.P., printed for joint meeting of Zamorano and Roxburghe Clubs, September, 1972
  - W.W. Robinson; 1974 1974 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    Eulogy by L.C.P. spoken at memorial service, September 6, 1974; reprinted for joint meeting of the Zamorano and Roxburghe Clubs, September ,1974
  - Up in Coconono County, by Patricia Paylore: Number Two of Southwest Broadsides 1953 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Printed by Ward Ritchie, Los Angeles 1953. An editorial by the President of the Arozona State Library Association. 8 1/4 x 11 inches. Two colors
  - A Speech in the United States Senate -- Given on June, 13,1935 by Henry Fountain Ashurst: Number Six of Southwest Broadsides 1955 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Printed by Richard Hoffman, LosAngeles 1955 20x26 inches. Heading in blue type and large eagle in red.
  - Rivers, by Harvey Fergusson: Number Elevenof Southwest Broadsides 1956 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Printed by Raphael Gonsalves and Edward Possnecke in the Graphic Arts Laboratories of Los Angeles City College under the supervision of Richard Hoffman. The illustration, drawn and hand cut by Gonsalves. was produced in 5 colors by the silk screen process. A few copies on Italian hand made Umbria paper, the rest on Shadowmould Cover 1956. 20 x20 inches
  - Land of the Southwest, by Paul Horgan: Number Twelve of Southwest Broadsides (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Printed at the Grabhorn Press, San Francisco, 1958. From the Southwest Review, Summer 1933. 16x 22 inches. Two colors
  - Return to the Heartland 1987 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    L.C.P. lecture announcement ,11 1/2" by 17"